# **Ismail Farhang**

Data Analyst | Oracle | PL/SQL | Al

## CONTACT

#### **ADDRESS:**

Dasht-e-Barchi, Kabul Afghanistan

PHONE:

+93773037027, +93785189777

**EMAIL:** 

Ismailfarhang01@gmail.com

## **LANGUAGES**

**DARI (NATIVE)** 

**PASHTO (INTERMEDIATE)** 

**ENGLISH (INTERMEDIATE)** 

# **COMPUTER SKILLS**

Familiar of various software such as; Windows, Linux, Office 365, Networking, Database and WordPress, Google and Microsoft (SPSS) Services.

# **STENGTHS**

- Data Analysis Proficiency
- Communication
- Business Mindset
- Project Management

## **AUTHOR AND RESEARCH**

WRITTEN ARTICLE in Role of ICT4D

in Afghanistan. (Department) june,2023 https.icti.com

**BACHELOR THESIS** in Search Engine

Optimization (google). (Certified by supervisor) Nov,2023.
Assistant Prof. M. Hanif Gharanai

#### **SUMMARY**

Enthusiastic Data Analyst in data analysis and oracle developer and visualize the datasets in tech/banking industry and I completed three projects based on UI/UX design through WordPress CMS. And then over 3 months of experience in DSCM and UCC portal on complex datasets into clear insights to manage the portals with strong decision-making processes, with a real record of Etisalat Customers processing and growth.

#### **SKILLS**

- SQL & Oracle DB
- Microsoft Excel
- Data Analysis
- Power BI
- Wordpress
- Al Tools

### **EDUCATION**

#### **Side Hustle Mastery Course**

**Musdaris Academy** 

2024-01-02 to 2024-03-05 Online

## **Digital Marketing & Business**

**Max business School** 

2023-10-25 to 2023-12-20 Online

#### Bachelor's degree in ICT Faculty

**University of Kabul** 

2019–2023 Kabul, Afghanistan

#### **Graduated from High School**

Mawlana Jalaluddin Mohammad Balkhi

2015 – 2018 Baluchistan, Pakistan

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Data Analysis Intern**

**Etisalat Afghanistan** 

2024-03-02 - 2024-06-05

Kabul, Afghanistan

Assisted in analytical techniques to improve business decision processes via data Interstation and Management

- Initiated the reduction in data redundancy by 40%, improving data consistency and integrity
- Collaborated with key business flagships to deliver insights, enhancing growth opportunities by 25%
- Performed deep analytical dives into problems to troubleshoot and identify root causes.

#### **Website Project**

**Hejran Travel Agency** 

2023-10-15 - 2023-11-05

Kabul, Afghanistan

Designed a WordPress website for a local business resulting in a 30% increase in online presence and a 15% growth in online sales

#### **CERTIFICATE**

Etisalat Afghanistan, Oracle for Data Analysis, Musdaris Academy, Max business School University of Kabul, Mawlana Jalaluddin Mohammad Balkhi

#### **OTHER ACTIVITIES**

Member of Kabul University Students' Union